Guide to the Thomas Merton Center Records, 1962-2009 AIS.1982.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Third Deposit (2000), 1977-2000; III.
  - Male Consciousness Raising-Hypermasculinity and the Military (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Neutron Bomb, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Japan Comemorations, 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Nevada Test Site Action, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - National Peace Academy, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - NATO Strategy, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - National Guard Association of Pennsylvania, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - United States Military Posts, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Military Budget/Pentagon Plan, 1981, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Nuclear Free Zones, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - North Atlantic Network, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Nuclear Free New Zealand, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Articles, Pamphlets, Newsletters on Nuclear Proliferation, 1982-1995 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Articles, Pamphlets, Newsletters on the Nuclear Freeze Movement, 1984-1996 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Articles, Pamphlets, Newsletters on the Middle East, 1983-1993 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - The New People Book Review on the Middle East, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Israeli Invasion of Lebanon, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Israeli Raid On Iraqi Nuclear Reactor, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Lebanon and the Middle East, 1983-1992 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Ernesto Cardenal, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - CEPAD Report, 1992-1993 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Mayor's Commission on Sister Cities Association (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Sister Cities: Pittsburgh-San Isidro Communications Commitee (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - San Isidro Sister City (contains photo and memo book) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, July 1994 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Sister City Delegation, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Report on Election in Nicaragua, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Events Photos (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Fundraisers, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Educational Materials, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Sister City Fundraising Committee (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - TMC Expenditures (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Western Union (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Sister City Humanitarian Aid, 1988-1990 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - MADRE (Human Rights for Women and Families) (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - San Isidro - Miscellaneous (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Shipments to Nicaragua, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Sister City Phone Tree (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - San Isidro Educational Brochure, Sister City Sprint (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Sister City Truck, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Pax Christi, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Sister Cities International, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Fundraisers: Ober Brau Fest, Great Race, Pottery (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Honduras, Janet Melvin's Articles, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Latin America (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Guatemala, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Ireland (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Immigration (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Human Rights (Box 41, Folder 30-31)
  - Guinea Bissau (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Iran, 1978-1985 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Grenada, 1989 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Korea, 1980s (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Libya, 1980s-1990s (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Haiti, 1988-1992 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Clinica Dental San Benito - Managua, Nicaragua, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Building New Hope, Central American Solar Energy Project, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Steel Valley Authority (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - General Agreement on the Corporate Charter (GACC), 1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Interfaith Alliance (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - JEDI Women (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Jobs with Justice (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Religious Task Force on the Economy (Box 42, Folder 6-9)
  - Istook Amendment (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - River City Campaign Meeting - Correspondence (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - River City Campaign Meeting with Westinghouse (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Pre-River City Slide Show Script (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - River City - Software Engineering Institute (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Tri-State Conference on Steel (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Living Wage, 1997-2000 (Box 42, Folder 16-22)
  - Sweat Shops, 2000 (Box 42, Folder 23-24)
  - Anti-Nuclear (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Left Politics (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - UE (Box 43, Folder 3-6)
  - TMC Resources (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Transcripts for Slide Shows (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Kosovo (Box 43, Folder 9-11)
  - Economic Conversion (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - NAFTA (Box 43, Folder 13-14)
  - Gulf War (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Bosnian Student Project (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Bosnia (Box 43, Folder 17-19)
  - AFL-CIO (Box 43, Folder 20-21)
  - Allegheny County Workers (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Labor Party (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Nabisco (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - St. Joseph Nursing Home / SEIU (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - PA Fair Trade Campaign (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Steel Valley Authority, 1999 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - UFWA Mushroom Pickers (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Pittsburgh Works (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Stop War Toys Campaign (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Privatization (Box 43, Folder 31-32)
  - WQEX TV (Box 43, Folder 33-34)
  - Mobilization for Survival
    - Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 44, Folder 1-7)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1977-1984 (Box 44, Folder 8-12)
    - The Mobilizer, MFS Publication (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - MSF National Conference, January 1981 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - MFS, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Anti-War Demonstration, April 14, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - United Nations Demonstration, May 27, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - March to Pentagon, May 3, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - MFS Paper Crane Project (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Nuclear Waste Issues (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Radium (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Uranium Mining (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Industrial Waste Issues (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Solar Energy (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Radioactive Materials Transportation (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Military Spending vs. Jobs / Employment (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Energy and Jobs (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Sea/Space Weapons (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Jobs with Peace (JWP) City of Pittsburgh Ballot Question, November 1982 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - JWP Mayor's Reports, 1982-1988 (Box 45, Folder 10-16)
    - Impact of Military Spending on Employment and Social Services: The 1989 Report (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Newsletters, Clippings, Records of Activities (Box 46, Folder 1-15)
- Fourth Deposit (2004), 1983-2004; IV.
  This series continues the typical organization of subject and operational files covering a variety of social justice issues, as well as records relating to Thomas Merton Center training, events, awards, internships and reports. The bulk of the material in this series pertains to the following: Issues/Groups, Economy/Citizens Budget Campaign of Western Pennsylvania (CBC), the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) and Cooperating/Affiliated groups.
  - TMC Media Coverage, 1986-2001 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Corita Print (Fund Raiser - Plowshares 8) (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Original Filers, Postcards, etc. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Advocacy Training, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 2001, 2003 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Dennis Brutus (Board Member) (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Directory - Peace, Justice, Ecology, original (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - TMC Co-sponsorships, 1995-2002 (Box 47, Folder 8-9)
  - East End Community Thrift Shop Fashion Show Programs, 1998-1999 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - TMC Events (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Economic Justice, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - John Dear SJ Retreat, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - S Janice McLaughlin, MM on Zimbabwe, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Merton Commemorations (annual event), 2003 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - May Day Stars of 20th Century, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Nagasaki Day, 1998 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Dorothy Day Birthday, 1997 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Rock Against Racism, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Urban Plunge (Annual Notre Dame Students), 2001 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Merton Awards, 1996-2001 (Box 47, Folder 22-24)
  - New Person Awards (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - Executive Service Corps, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Internships, 1995-1997 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - New People, 2001-2002 (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - TMC Board (incomplete), 1999-2003 (Box 47, Folder 29-30)
  - Notes on Staff Meetings (incomplete), 1988-2003 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - Strategic Planning (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Grant Information, 2001 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - TMC Website (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - September 11 and Beyond (Box 47, Folder 35-40)
  - Church War / Peace (Box 47, Folder 41)
  - Civil Liberties (Box 47, Folder 42)
  - Terrorism (Box 47, Folder 43)
  - Statements on Afghan War / Crisis (Box 47, Folder 44)
  - Afghan Refugees (Box 47, Folder 45)
  - Iraq Actions/Clippings, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 46-48)
  - Neighborhood Collaboratives Against Racism, Training Manual (Box 47, Folder 49)
  - Issues/Groups
    - Childcare Organizing (Virtual Strike), 2002 (Box 47, Folder 50)
    - Coalition / Hate Groups (Box 47, Folder 51)
    - Criminal Justice Publications (Box 47, Folder 52)
    - Death Penalty / Conference, 2001-2002 (Box 47, Folder 53)
    - Getu Tewolfe (immigrant jailed), 2002 (Box 47, Folder 54)
    - Gulf War, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    - Gun Control, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 56)
    - Israel / Palestine, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 57)
    - Labor, 1985-2003 (Box 47, Folder 58)
    - Latin America / Sen. Specter, 1988-2002 (Box 47, Folder 59-61)
    - Childhood Lead Poisoning / Herb Needleman, 1992-1994 (Box 47, Folder 62)
    - Prison Issues, 1983-1985 (Box 47, Folder 63-64)
    - Rwandan Students - La Roche College (Box 47, Folder 65-66)
    - School of the Americas / Roy Bourgeois (Box 47, Folder 67)
    - South Africa Miners Support, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 68)
    - Terrorism, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 69)
    - Violence, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 70)
    - Welfare Reform Liaison Project, Inc., 1999 (Box 47, Folder 71)
    - Misc. / Nuclear Weapons - CMU, 1980 (Box 47, Folder 72-73)
    - Abolition, 1999-2002 (Box 47, Folder 74-75)
    - Arms Race Study Group, University of Pittsburgh, 1980-1989 (Box 47, Folder 76)
    - Chain of Life / Ribbon Events, 1983-1984 (Box 47, Folder 77)
    - CMU Program on Peace and Security, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 78)
    - De-Alerting Drama, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 79)
    - Election 2000 Nuclear Weapons (Box 47, Folder 80)
    - Faculty for Social Responsibility U. of Pittsburgh, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 81)
    - 40 Years After Peace Week, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 82)
    - Great Peace March, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 83)
    - Nuclear Waste and Health, 1983-1996 (Box 47, Folder 84)
    - Health Studies of Radiation, 1975, 1982-1983 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Nuclear Waste Shipments, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Peace Crane, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Coalition to Prevent Nuclear War, 1985-1986 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Pittsburgh Peace Network (UN Rally), 1982 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Seneca Peace Camp, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Sprawl (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - UN Special Session on Disarmament, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Duquesne University - Western PA Campaign for CTB, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Photo of CMU's Software Engineering Institute (SEI) funded by Pentagon (filed sideways) (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Sample of Cartoons Used in New People (filed sideways) (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Economy / Citizens Budget Campaign of Western PA (CBC)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Military Iraq, 2001-2004 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Poverty: Call to Renewal Bus Tour, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Women's Budget Project, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Corporate Issues, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - The Economy / Trade, 1999-2004 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Environment / Oil, 2002-2004 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Inequality (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Jobs, 2001-2004 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - National Priorities Project, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sweatshops, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Wal-Mart (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Church Statements on Economic Justice, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Religious Task Force on the Economy, 1997-2000 (Box 48, Folder 25-26)
    - Keystone Minimum Wage, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Common Sense/CBC National, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - Program on Corporations Law and Democracy, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - Congressional Voting Records, 1998-1999 (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - CMU the Military, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Disarmament, 1985-1994 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Hiroshima, 1971, 1977 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Military Budget, 1981-2004 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Missile Defense, 2000-2004 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - Nuclear Bomb Policy, 1998-2004 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Nuclear Waste Workers, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility, 2002-2004 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Smart Security (Alliance for Nuclear Accountability), 1999-2004 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Terrorism "The Bomb", 2002 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Helen Woodson, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - Citizens Budget Campaign, 2001-2003 (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Business Taxes in PA, 2003 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - National Military Budget, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - Environment, 1991-2004 (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - Corporate Issues (CEO pay, etc.), 2004 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - Economy Wages / Corporate, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - Pgh. Economy, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 48)
    - Local/State Tax Disparities, 2003 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - Citizens for Global Solutions, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 50)
    - Iraq, 2000-2004 (Box 48, Folder 51)
    - Jobs - Overtime, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    - Poverty / Income Taxes / Welfare, 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    - War Resisters League - Military Spending, 1998-2003 (Box 48, Folder 54)
    - Hearing with Rep. Mike Doyle, July 1, 2003 (Box 48, Folder 55)
    - Minutes (incomplete) / Electoral Campaigns, 1997-2002 (Box 48, Folder 56-57)
    - Brochures, Filers (Box 48, Folder 58-60)
    - City Council Hearing: Impact of Budget Cuts on Pgh., 2002 (Box 48, Folder 61)
    - Economic Stats - PNC, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - PA Budget (Box 48, Folder 63)
    - Status of Women in PA (Box 48, Folder 64)
    - Mailing Lists, 1999-2003 (Box 48, Folder 65-67)
    - Human Needs over Greed March and Rally, 2003 (Box 48, Folder 68)
    - Federal Deficit, 2003-2004 (Box 48, Folder 69)
    - Tax Cuts, 2001-2003 (Box 48, Folder 70)
    - Articles and Letters, 2002-2003 (Box 48, Folder 71)
    - PA and Federal Budget, 2002-2003 (Box 48, Folder 72)
    - Ensuring Prosperity For All Statement and Wizard is Odd Skit, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 73)
    - Star Wars Skit, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 74)
    - Pittsburgh Redevelopment Plans, 2000 (Box 48, Folder 75)
    - Rick Santorum Protest, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 76)
    - Robert Bowman Event on Military Spending / Star Wars, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 77)
    - Jane Blotzer Post-Gazette Series on Inequality, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 78)
    - Agenda for Action / Religious Community, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 79)
    - Church Statements (Box 48, Folder 80)
    - Budgeting for the Common Good, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Day Without the Pentagon, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - National Agenda for Action (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Tax Day Actions, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Letters to the Editor, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Focus on Inequality Workshops, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - March and Rally, October 1, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - CBC Lobby - Tax Cuts, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Wizard is Odd Skit, March 7, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - City Council Hearing, May 6, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Rebate the Rebate, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - It's Your Money, It's Your Vote Campaign, 1999-2000 (Box 49, Folder 12-16)
    - Building a Just Economy, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 17-27)
    - State and Local Taxes (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Pittsburgh Budget, 2003-2004 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Allegheny County, 1995, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - PA Demographics, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Inequality, PA, 2000-2003 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - PA Tax Info, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - State Budget, 2002-2003 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Bush Tax Cut, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - U.S. Economy, 2002-2003 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - National Priority Project, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Federal Taxes / Estate Tax, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 39-40)
    - Enron, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    - International Monetary Fund (IMF) / North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) (Box 49, Folder 42)
    - Global Business, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 43)
    - Paul O'Neill, 2004 (Box 49, Folder 44)
    - Elected Officials - Congress (Box 49, Folder 45-46)
    - Stimulus Package, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - Women and the Economy (Box 49, Folder 48)
  - Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP)
    - General Reports (Box 49, Folder 49)
    - Inequality (Box 49, Folder 50)
    - Inequality Articles (Not by CBPP) (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - Taxes and Other (Box 49, Folder 52)
    - International (Box 49, Folder 53)
    - Poverty (Box 49, Folder 54)
    - Social Security (Box 49, Folder 55)
    - State Issues (Box 49, Folder 56)
  - Cooperating or Affiliated Groups
    - AFL-CIO, 1996-2002 (Box 49, Folder 57)
    - Allegheny Institute (Not affiliated), 1996 (Box 49, Folder 58)
    - Alliance for Progressive Action, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 59)
    - Living Wage Campaigns, 1998-2002 (Box 49, Folder 60)
    - Association of Pittsburgh Priests, 2001-2004 (Box 49, Folder 61-64)
    - Carrol, James (Box 49, Folder 65)
    - Black and White Reunion, 2002 (Box 49, Folder 66-67)
    - Citizens for Consumer Justice, 2000-2001 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Clean Water Action, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Committee for Appropriate Acknowledgment (Bayer Nazis), 1999 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Consumer Health Coalition, 2000-2002 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Earth Day, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Gang Peace Council (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Good Schools PA, 2001-2002 (Box 50, Folder 7-8)
    - Haiti Solidarity Committee, 2000-2004 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Hearts and Hands Together, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Islamic Center of Pittsburgh, 1995-2000 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - INFACT (Kraft / Phillip Morris Boycott / Protest), 1999 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Just Harvest, 2001 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Media Campaigns, 1995-1997 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Mainstream Media (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - PCTV - Pittsburgh Cable (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Mexican Solidarity, 1999-2000 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Million Mom March, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Mon Valley Unemployed Committee, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - National Conference for Community and Justice (NCCJ) / Pax Christi Pittsburgh, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 20-21)
    - Pennsylvania Hunger Advocate Newsletter, December 1997 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - PA Low Income Housing Coalition, 2000-2001 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Pittsburgh Social Forum (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Pittsburgh Interfaith Impact Network / Gamaliel Foundation, 2000-2002 (Box 50, Folder 25-29)
    - Pittsburgh Peace Institute, 1977-1990 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - PLANTA (Sweatshops), 2001 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - Religion and Labor Council, 2000-2002 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - Jack O'Malley, Labor Priest (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - Religious Task Force on the Economy, 1997-2001 (Box 50, Folder 34-35)
    - Save Our Sons and Daughters (SO SAD) (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Stand for Children, 1999-2000 (Box 50, Folder 37-38)
    - Children's Sabbath, 1998 (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - Three Rivers Fund, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Sisters of Mercy - Together Against Violence / Violence Symposium, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 41-42)
    - United Religious Initiatives, 2000 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - World Federalists Association of Pittsburgh, 2000-2002 (Box 50, Folder 44-46)
- Fifth Deposit (2009), 1962-2009; V.
  This series contains a variety of Thomas Merton Center records from the years 1962-2009 and is organized into three subseries: Administrative Files, Subject Files and Audio/Visual. Administrative Files include records pertaining to the running of the Center. Subject Files include records pertaining to peace and social justice issues as well as a significant run of the Center's peace and justice newspaper, The New People, covering the years 1974-2008, though certain issues are missing, particularly from the 2000s. Audio/Visual includes photographs, slideshows, cassette tapes, sound reels, and VHS tapes, covering Center events and peace and social justice issues. Records are organized alphabetically within each subseries.
  - Administrative Files, 1980-2009; 1.
    Documenting the organization and administration of the Thomas Merton Center, these records include: volunteer records; financial/budget documents; board/staff documents; Center projects; staff and member retreats; and celebrations such as the Center's yearly award dinner recognizing an individual for their work in peace and social justice. A significant part of the subseries includes Giving Tree records, the alternative holiday gift shop run by the Center to support workers in third-world countries. The administration subseries includes materials from 1980 to 2009.
    - Advocacy Training, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Annual Members Meeting, ca. 1997 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Board and Steering Committee, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 3-4)
    - Board/Staff, 1982-1983 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Board/Staff, 1984 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Board/Staff, 1985-1986 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Board/Staff, ca. 1987 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Board/Staff, ca. 1988-1989 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Board/Staff, ca. 1990 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Board/Staff, 1990-1991 (Box 51, Folder 11-12)
    - Board/Staff, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Board/Staff, 1993-1994 (Box 51, Folder 14-15)
    - Board/Staff, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Board/Staff Retreats, 1985-1991 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Mayor Tom Murphy, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - East End Community Thrift Shop Volunteers List, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Giving Tree, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Giving Tree, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Giving Tree, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Giving Tree Ad and Logo Design, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Giving Tree Banner/Sign Design, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Giving Tree Events, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Giving Tree Events, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Giving Tree: Ideas from Old Staff, Etc. (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Giving Tree Job and Volunteer Descriptions, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Giving Tree Loans, 1986-1999 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Giving Tree Press Releases, 1989-1993 (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1988 (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1992 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 34)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 35)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 36)
    - Giving Tree Records, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 37)
    - Intern Evaluation, Elaine Kuhar, 2006 (Box 51, Folder 38)
    - Internship Information, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 39)
    - Letter to Board of Directors, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 40)
    - New People Article Submission, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 41)
    - New People Information, 2002 (Box 51, Folder 42)
    - New People Statistics, 1991-1993 (Box 51, Folder 43)
    - New Person Award, 1986 (Box 51, Folder 44)
    - New Person Award, Anne Feeney, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 45)
    - New Person Award, Labor and Community Solidarity, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 46)
    - Peacemaker Series--TMC 30th Anniversary, 2002 (Box 51, Folder 47)
    - Staff/Community Networking--Kevin Amos, 2008 (Box 51, Folder 48)
    - Strategy Committee, 1993 (Box 51, Folder 49)
    - Summer Retreat Merton House, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 50)